<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>index</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:39:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:39:29 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Glossary]]></title><description><![CDATA[A Record - A DNS record type that maps a domain name to an IPv4 address. The most common DNS record type.AAAA Record - A DNS record type that maps a domain name to an IPv6 address (128-bit).Access Control - Security mechanisms that regulate who or what can view or use resources in a computing environment.Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS) - Microsoft's directory service that manages users, computers, and other objects in a Windows domain network. Provides authentication, authorization, and centralized administration.Advanced Forensic Format (AFF) - An open-source, extensible forensic image format supporting compression, encryption, metadata, and advanced features. Designed to be patent-free and vendor-neutral.Adversary - An individual, group, organization, or government that conducts or has the intent to conduct detrimental activities against an organization or system.API (Application Programming Interface) - A set of protocols, tools, and definitions that allows different software applications to communicate with each other.APT (Advanced Persistent Threat) - A prolonged and targeted cyber attack in which an intruder gains access to a network and remains undetected for an extended period, often to steal data.ARPANET - Advanced Research Projects Agency Network, the precursor to the modern internet, developed by the U.S. Department of Defense in the late 1960s.Asset - Anything of value to an organization, including data, hardware, software, facilities, personnel, and reputation.Attack - Any kind of malicious activity that attempts to collect, disrupt, deny, degrade, or destroy information system resources or the information itself.Attack Surface - The total sum of vulnerabilities, pathways, and methods that an attacker could use to gain unauthorized access to a system or network.Audit Trail - A chronological record of system activities that provides documentary evidence of sequences of activities affecting a specific operation or event.Authentication - The process of verifying the identity of a user, device, or system. In cryptography, verifying that a user is who they claim to be.Authoritative Name Server - The DNS server that has the actual DNS records for a specific domain. It provides the definitive answer for queries about that domain.Automation - The use of technology to perform tasks with minimal human intervention, often through scripts or dedicated tools.Availability - Ensuring that authorized users have reliable and timely access to information and resources when needed. One of the three pillars of the CIA Triad.Backup - A copy of data stored separately from the original to protect against data loss from hardware failure, corruption, or deletion.Biometrics - Authentication method using unique physical characteristics such as fingerprints, facial recognition, iris scans, or voice patterns.Black Box - Something that you can't see how it works. In security testing, testing where the tester has no knowledge of the internal workings of the system.Black Box Testing - Security testing where the tester has no knowledge of the internal workings of the system, simulating an external attack.Blue Team - A group responsible for defending against attacks and improving security posture.California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) - Similar provisions as GDPR for residents of California.Chain of Custody (CoC) - A documented chronological record that tracks the handling, transfer, location, and possession of physical or electronic evidence from collection through presentation in court. Essential for maintaining evidence integrity and admissibility.CIA Triad - The three foundational principles of information security: Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability. Sometimes expanded to include Authentication, Authorization, Accounting, and Non-repudiation.CLI (Command-Line Interface) - A text-based interface where users interact with the system by typing commands.Clone - An exact duplicate of a storage device that can be used to replace the original device. Unlike an image, a clone is a physical device-to-device copy that can be booted and used operationally.Cloud Computing - The delivery of computing services (servers, storage, databases, networking, software) over the internet ("the cloud").CNAME Record (Canonical Name) - A DNS record that creates an alias for another domain name, allowing one domain to point to another.Compliance - Adherence to laws, regulations, standards, and policies that apply to an organization's industry and operations.Computer Fraud and Abuse Act (CFAA) - Anyone who engages in unauthorized computer access faces consequences ranging from fines to imprisonment.Confidentiality - Using cryptography to keep data private. Ensuring that information is accessible only to those authorized to access it. One of the three pillars of the CIA Triad.Containerization - A lightweight alternative to virtualization that packages applications and their dependencies together, allowing them to run consistently across different computing environments (e.g., Docker).Contamination - Any alteration, addition, or deletion of evidence data that compromises its integrity and admissibility in legal proceedings.Creeper - The first documented computer virus (1971), a self-replicating program that displayed the message "I'm the creeper, catch me if you can!"Cryptographic Salt - A random string of characters added to a password before hashing to protect against rainbow table attacks and ensure unique hashes even for identical passwords.CVE (Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures) - A publicly disclosed security vulnerability identified by a unique ID (e.g., CVE-2021-44228 for Log4Shell).Data Breach - An incident where sensitive, protected, or confidential data is accessed, disclosed, or stolen by an unauthorized individual.DDoS (Distributed Denial of Service) - A DoS attack that uses multiple compromised systems (often a botnet) to flood the target with traffic.Defense in Depth - A security strategy that employs multiple layers of defense mechanisms to protect assets, so that if one layer fails, others continue to provide protection.DHCP (Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol) - A network protocol that automatically assigns IP addresses and other network configuration parameters to devices on a network.Digital Certificate - An electronic document that uses a digital signature to bind a public key with an identity (person or organization). Issued by Certificate Authorities (CAs).Digital Signature - A cryptographic mechanism that provides authentication, integrity, and non-repudiation by using public key cryptography to "sign" data.DMZ (Demilitarized Zone) - A physical or logical subnetwork that contains and exposes external-facing services to an untrusted network, usually the internet, while keeping the internal network secure.DNS (Domain Name System) - A hierarchical distributed naming system that translates human-readable domain names (like <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://www.google.com" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://www.google.com" target="_self">www.google.com</a>) into IP addresses that computers use to identify each other on networks.DNS Caching - The temporary storage of DNS query results to speed up subsequent lookups and reduce network traffic.Domain Controller - A Windows server running AD DS that authenticates users and computers in a Windows domain, enforces security policies, and stores the Active Directory database.DoS (Denial of Service) - An attack that makes a system, network, or service unavailable to legitimate users by overwhelming it with traffic or exploiting vulnerabilities.EnCase Expert Witness Format (EWF/E01) - A proprietary forensic image format that supports compression, encryption, metadata storage, hashing, and splitting files into manageable segments.Encryption - The process of encoding information so that only authorized parties can access it, typically using cryptographic algorithms and keys.Evidence Container - A file format designed to store forensic images along with metadata. Examples include E01 (EnCase) and AFF (Advanced Forensic Format).Exploit - A piece of software, data, or sequence of commands that takes advantage of a vulnerability to cause unintended behavior in a system.File Services - Windows Server role that provides technologies for storage management, file replication, distributed namespace management, and shared folder access.Firewall - A network security device or software that monitors and controls incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules.Forensic Image - A bit-by-bit copy of a storage device that captures all data including active files, deleted files, slack space, and unallocated space. Unlike a simple copy, it preserves metadata and can be validated using cryptographic hashes.Forensics - The application of scientific methods to collect, preserve, analyze, and present evidence from digital devices in a manner acceptable in legal proceedings.FTK (Forensic Toolkit) Format - A proprietary format from AccessData with similar features to EWF, supporting metadata, compression, encryption, and file splitting.FTP (File Transfer Protocol) - A standard network protocol used to transfer files between a client and server over a network.Gateway - A network node that serves as an access point to another network, often performing protocol translation.General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) - A law that protects the personal private data for citizens of the European Union.Geofencing - Only allowing access from specific locations.Gray Box Testing - Security testing where the tester has partial knowledge of the system, combining elements of white box and black box testing.GUI (Graphical User Interface) - A user interface that allows interaction with electronic devices through graphical icons and visual indicators, as opposed to text-based command-line interfaces.Hash Value - A unique fixed-length string generated by a cryptographic algorithm from data of any size. Used to verify data integrity. Also called a "fingerprint" or "digest."Healthcare Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) - A law that protects the Protected Health Information (PHI).HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol) - The foundation of data communication on the World Wide Web, defining how messages are formatted and transmitted.HTTPS (HTTP Secure) - An extension of HTTP that uses encryption (TLS/SSL) to secure communication between web browsers and servers.Hypervisor - Software that creates and runs virtual machines by abstracting the underlying physical hardware.IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service) - Cloud computing model providing virtualized computing resources over the internet (e.g., AWS EC2, Azure VMs).ICANN - Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers. Manages the DNS root zone.IDS (Intrusion Detection System) - A system that monitors network traffic for suspicious activity and alerts administrators to potential security breaches.IETF - Internet Engineering Task Force, an open standards organization that develops and promotes voluntary internet standards, particularly those comprising the Internet Protocol Suite (TCP/IP).Impact - The magnitude of harm that could result from a threat exploiting a vulnerability. Can be measured in financial, operational, or reputational terms.Impersonation - Pretending to be someone else to gain unauthorized access to systems, information, or physical locations. A common physical security threat.Incident - An event that violates or threatens to violate security policies, acceptable use policies, or standard security practices.Incident Response - The systematic approach to managing and addressing security incidents, including preparation, detection, containment, eradication, recovery, and lessons learned.Indicator of Compromise (IoC) - Forensic evidence that suggests a system has been breached or infected, such as unusual network traffic, file modifications, or suspicious registry changes.Integrity - Using cryptography to ensure that data has not been altered. Maintaining the accuracy, consistency, and trustworthiness of data throughout its lifecycle. One of the three pillars of the CIA Triad.Internet - Global network of computers.IoT - Internet of Things, often in reference to "smart home" electronics.IP Address (Internet Protocol Address) - A numerical label assigned to each device connected to a network that uses IP for communication. Can be IPv4 (32-bit) or IPv6 (128-bit).IPS (Intrusion Prevention System) - An active security system that monitors network traffic and can automatically take action to block or prevent detected threats.IPv4 - Version 4 of the Internet Protocol using 32-bit addresses (e.g., 192.168.1.1), providing approximately 4.3 billion unique addresses.IPv6 - Version 6 of the Internet Protocol using 128-bit addresses (e.g., 2001:0db8:85a3::8a2e:0370:7334), providing vastly more unique addresses than IPv4.ISP (Internet Service Provider) - A company that provides internet access to customers.LAN (Local Area Network) - A network that connects computers and devices in a limited geographical area like a home, office, or building.Least Privilege Principle - Giving people the minimum access required to do their jobs. A security concept requiring that users, processes, and systems be granted only the minimum levels of access necessary to perform their functions.Live Acquisition - The process of collecting digital evidence from a powered-on, running system. Captures volatile data like RAM contents, running processes, and active network connections, but risks contamination.Logical Acquisition - Copying specific files, folders, or partitions from a storage device rather than imaging the entire physical device.MAC Address (Media Access Control Address) - A unique hardware identifier assigned to network interface cards, used for communication within a local network segment.Malware - Short for "malicious software." Any software intentionally designed to cause damage, gain unauthorized access, or perform unwanted actions on a computer system.McCumber Cube - Represents design aspects for securing data in every level of abstraction.MD5 (Message Digest 5) - A cryptographic hash function that produces a 128-bit hash value. Widely used for integrity verification in forensics, though cryptographically broken for security purposes.Multifactor Authentication - The use of a secondary device(s) or media(s) for authentication, on top of the typical username/password.MX Record (Mail Exchange) - A DNS record that specifies the mail servers responsible for accepting email for a domain.NAT (Network Address Translation) - A method of remapping IP addresses by modifying network address information in packet headers, commonly used to allow multiple devices on a private network to share a single public IP address.Non-Repudiation - Ensure that user performed activity by proof that they cannot deny. Typically achieved through digital signatures and digital certificates.Norman Doors - Confusing or misleading user experiences. Design elements that provide confusing or misleading cues about their operation, named after Don Norman. In security contexts, refers to poor user interface design that leads to user errors and potential security issues.NSFNET - National Science Foundation Network, which replaced ARPANET in 1990 and later became the backbone of the modern internet before being decommissioned in 1995.Open Systems Interconnection (OSI) Model - Network protocol framework that uses 7 layers.Order of Volatility - The sequence in which digital evidence should be collected, based on how quickly the data will be lost. From most to least volatile: CPU cache, RAM, network connections, running processes, disk storage, backups.OSINT - Open Source Intelligence.PaaS (Platform as a Service) - Cloud computing model providing a platform allowing customers to develop, run, and manage applications without managing underlying infrastructure (e.g., Azure App Service, Heroku).Packet - A unit of data transmitted over a network. Contains both the payload (actual data) and header information (addressing, routing, error checking).Password Complexity - Requirements for passwords to include a mix of uppercase, lowercase, numbers, and special characters to increase security.Password Manager - A tool to organize and secure one's passwords for online services. A tool that stores and organizes passwords in an encrypted database, allowing users to maintain unique, complex passwords for different services.Patch - A software update designed to fix bugs, address security vulnerabilities, or improve functionality.Payload - The component of malware that performs the malicious action, such as stealing data, encrypting files, or opening a backdoor.Penetration Testing (Pen Testing) - Authorized simulated cyber attacks performed to evaluate the security of a system or network.PHI (Protected Health Information) - Any information about health status, provision of healthcare, or payment for healthcare that can be linked to a specific individual. Protected under HIPAA.Phishing - A social engineering attack using fraudulent emails, messages, or websites to trick victims into revealing sensitive information or installing malware.Physical Acquisition - Creating a complete bit-by-bit copy of an entire storage device, including all sectors, whether allocated or not.PII (Personally Identifiable Information) - Any data that could potentially identify a specific individual, including names, addresses, Social Security numbers, biometric data, etc.Port - A numbered endpoint in a network connection used to identify specific processes or services. Examples: HTTP uses port 80, HTTPS uses port 443.PowerShell - Microsoft's task automation and configuration management framework consisting of a command-line shell and scripting language built on .NET.Principle of Least Privilege - A security concept requiring that users, processes, and systems be granted only the minimum levels of access necessary to perform their functions.Protocol - A set of rules and standards that define how data is transmitted and received over a network. Examples: TCP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, DNS, DHCP.PTR Record (Pointer Record) - A DNS record used for reverse DNS lookups, mapping an IP address back to a domain name.Purple Team - A collaborative approach where red and blue teams work together to improve security through shared knowledge.Ransomware - Malicious software that encrypts a victim's files or locks their system, demanding payment (ransom) to restore access. Example: WannaCry.Raw Image (dd) - A bit-by-bit copy of a storage device with no compression, metadata, or error handling. File extension is typically .dd or .raw.RBAC (Role-Based Access Control) - An access control method where permissions are assigned to roles rather than individuals, and users are assigned to appropriate roles.RDP (Remote Desktop Protocol) - A proprietary protocol developed by Microsoft that provides a graphical interface for connecting to another computer over a network.Red Team - A group that plays the role of attackers to test an organization's security defenses.Resolving Name Server - A DNS server (also called a recursive resolver) that receives DNS queries from clients and performs the necessary lookups to return the corresponding IP address. Typically provided by ISPs or can be set manually (like Google's 8.8.8.8).Restore - The process of recovering data from a backup to return systems or files to a previous state.Risk - The potential for loss, damage, or destruction of assets as a result of a threat exploiting a vulnerability. Typically calculated as Risk = Threat × Vulnerability × Impact.Root Domain Server - The top-level DNS servers in the DNS hierarchy that know the locations of all TLD (Top-Level Domain) name servers. There are 13 root server systems worldwide (labeled A through M).Router - A networking device that forwards data packets between computer networks, determining the best path for data transmission.SaaS (Software as a Service) - Cloud computing model where applications are hosted by a provider and made available to customers over the internet (e.g., Office 365, Salesforce).Sandbox - An isolated testing environment that allows programs to run without affecting the system or other applications, used for testing potentially malicious code or new features.Script - A program or sequence of instructions that is interpreted or executed by another program rather than compiled into machine code.Security Awareness Training - Education programs designed to help users recognize and respond to security threats like phishing, social engineering, and malware.Security by Design - The practice of building security into systems from the beginning of development rather than adding it later.Server Core - A minimal installation option for Windows Server that runs without a graphical user interface (GUI), reducing attack surface and resource requirements.SHA-1 (Secure Hash Algorithm 1) - A cryptographic hash function producing a 160-bit hash value. Previously standard but now deprecated for security use due to collision vulnerabilities. Still used in forensics for legacy compatibility.SHA-2 - A family of cryptographic hash functions including SHA-224, SHA-256, SHA-384, and SHA-512. Currently recommended for security and integrity verification.SIEM (Security Information and Event Management) - A system that aggregates and analyzes security data from across an organization's infrastructure to detect threats and manage incidents.Single Sign-On (SSO) - An authentication scheme allowing users to log in once and gain access to multiple related systems without re-entering credentials.Slack Space - The unused space between the end of a file and the end of the disk cluster it occupies. May contain remnants of previously deleted data.SOC (Security Operations Center) - A centralized facility where security professionals monitor, detect, analyze, and respond to cybersecurity incidents.Social Engineering - Psychological manipulation tactics used to trick people into divulging confidential information or performing actions that compromise security.SRV Record (Service Locator) - A DNS record that specifies the location (hostname and port) of servers for specific services like SIP, LDAP, or XMPP.SSH (Secure Shell) - A cryptographic network protocol for operating network services securely over an unsecured network, commonly used for remote command-line login.Static Acquisition - The process of collecting digital evidence from a powered-off system. Typically involves removing the storage device and connecting it through a write-blocker.Steganography - The practice of concealing information within another message or physical object to avoid detection. The practice of concealing messages or information within other non-secret data, such as hiding text within an image file.Stuxnet - First documented virus with real world physical damage, targeted Iran nuclear facilities. A sophisticated computer worm discovered in 2010, notable for being the first documented malware designed to cause real-world physical damage.Subnet (Subnetwork) - A logical subdivision of an IP network, allowing network administrators to divide a larger network into smaller, manageable segments.Switch - A network device that connects devices within a network and uses MAC addresses to forward data to the correct destination.Tailgating - A physical security breach where an unauthorized person follows an authorized person into a restricted area. Common physical security threat.TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) - A connection-oriented protocol that ensures reliable, ordered delivery of data between applications over a network.The Web - Collection of info accessed using internet.Threat - Anything that can exploit a vulnerability, intentionally or accidentally, and obtain, damage, or destroy an asset.Threat Intelligence - Information about current or emerging threats that helps organizations understand and mitigate risks.TLD Name Server (Top-Level Domain) - DNS servers responsible for top-level domains like .com, .org, .edu, .gov, or country codes like .uk, .jp. They know the authoritative name servers for all domains under their TLD.TLS/SSL (Transport Layer Security / Secure Sockets Layer) - Cryptographic protocols that provide secure communication over a network. SSL is the deprecated predecessor to TLS.UDP (User Datagram Protocol) - A connectionless protocol that sends data without establishing a connection or guaranteeing delivery, used for time-sensitive applications like video streaming.Unallocated Space - Areas of a storage device that are not currently assigned to any file. Often contains deleted files or fragments of deleted data.Update - A newer version of software that may include patches, new features, performance improvements, or security enhancements.URL (Uniform Resource Locator) - The address used to access resources on the internet, specifying the protocol, domain, path, and potentially query parameters.Validation - The process of verifying that a forensic image is identical to the source evidence, typically using hash algorithms like MD5, SHA-1, or SHA-2.Virtual Machine (VM) - A software emulation of a physical computer that runs an operating system and applications as if it were a physical machine.Virtualization - The creation of virtual (rather than physical) versions of computing resources like servers, storage devices, or networks.VPN (Virtual Private Network) - A technology that creates a secure, encrypted connection over a less secure network, such as the internet.Vulnerability - Weakness in an information system, system security procedures, internal controls, or implementation that could be exploited or triggered by a threat source. A weakness in a system, application, or network that could be exploited by threats to gain unauthorized access or cause harm.Vulnerability Assessment - The systematic process of identifying, quantifying, and prioritizing vulnerabilities in a system.WAN (Wide Area Network) - A network that covers a broad area, connecting multiple LANs across cities, countries, or continents.Wannacry - Infamous ransomware. A ransomware attack in May 2017 that infected over 200,000 computers across 150 countries, exploiting a Windows vulnerability and causing billions in damages.White Box Testing - Security testing where the tester has full knowledge of the internal structure, design, and code of the system being tested.World Wide Web - An information system where documents and resources are identified by URLs, interlinked by hypertext, and accessible via the internet. Invented by Tim Berners-Lee in 1991.Write-Blocker - A hardware or software tool that allows read-only access to data storage devices, preventing any modification of evidence during forensic examination.Zero Trust - A security model based on the principle "never trust, always verify," requiring strict identity verification for everyone trying to access resources regardless of location.Zero-Day Exploit - An attack that exploits a previously unknown vulnerability before the software vendor has released a patch.]]></description><link>glossary.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Glossary.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:38:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[FOR-120 Overview]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<a data-href="Evidence Acquisition" href="for-120/evidence-acquisition.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Evidence Acquisition</a> - Proper handling and preservation
<br><a data-href="Forensic Image Formats" href="for-120/forensic-image-formats.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Forensic Image Formats</a> - Understanding evidence containers <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary &gt; Chain of Custody" data-href="Glossary#Chain of Custody" href="glossary.html#Chain of Custody" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chain of Custody</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Evidence Acquisition &gt; Validating Data Acquisition" data-href="Evidence Acquisition#Validating Data Acquisition" href="for-120/evidence-acquisition.html#Validating Data Acquisition" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Hash Validation</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Evidence Acquisition &gt; Physical vs Logical Acquisition" data-href="Evidence Acquisition#Physical vs Logical Acquisition" href="for-120/evidence-acquisition.html#Physical vs Logical Acquisition" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Acquisition Methods</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Evidence Acquisition &gt; Live vs Static Acquisition" data-href="Evidence Acquisition#Live vs Static Acquisition" href="for-120/evidence-acquisition.html#Live vs Static Acquisition" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Live vs Static</a> <br>Cryptography: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="SEC-110/Module 5 &amp; 6 - Cryptography and Ciphers" data-href="SEC-110/Module 5 &amp; 6 - Cryptography and Ciphers" href="sec-110/module-5-&amp;-6-cryptography-and-ciphers.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Hashing algorithms</a>
<br>Legal Framework: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="SEC-110/Module 3 &amp; 4 - System Security" data-href="SEC-110/Module 3 &amp; 4 - System Security" href="sec-110/module-3-&amp;-4-system-security.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Compliance laws</a>
<br>Network Forensics: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="SEC-110/Module 10 - Network Security" data-href="SEC-110/Module 10 - Network Security" href="sec-110/module-10-network-security.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Network security</a> Evidence collection procedures
Hash validation practice
Chain of custody documentation
]]></description><link>for-120/for-120-overview.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">FOR-120/FOR-120 Overview.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:27:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[SYS-255 Overview]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="ADDS" data-href="ADDS" href="sys-255/adds.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Active Directory Domain Services</a>
<br><a data-href="DNS (Domain Name System)" href="sys-255/dns-(domain-name-system).html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">DNS (Domain Name System)</a>
<br><a data-href="DHCP" href="sys-255/dhcp.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">DHCP</a>
<br><a data-href="File Services" href="sys-255/file-services.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">File Services</a>
<br><a data-href="Core Network Services" href=".html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Core Network Services</a> - How they work together <br><a data-href="Server Core" href="sys-255/server-core.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Server Core</a> - Minimal installation
<br><a data-href="Apache" href="sys-255/apache.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Apache</a> - Web services
<br><a data-href="Linux" href="sys-255/linux.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Linux</a> - Linux administration <br><a data-href="Powershell" href="sys-255/powershell.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Powershell</a> - Windows automation
<br><a data-href="Bash" href="sys-255/bash.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bash</a> - Linux scripting <br><a data-href="Lab Setup" href="sys-255/lab-setup.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lab Setup</a> - Environment configuration <br>Security: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="SEC-110/Module 3 &amp; 4 - System Security" data-href="SEC-110/Module 3 &amp; 4 - System Security" href="sec-110/module-3-&amp;-4-system-security.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">System security principles</a>
<br>Networking: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="SEC-110/Module 10 - Network Security" data-href="SEC-110/Module 10 - Network Security" href="sec-110/module-10-network-security.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Network security</a>
]]></description><link>sys-255/sys-255-overview.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/SYS-255 Overview.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:26:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[SEC-110 Overview]]></title><description><![CDATA[
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 1 - What is Cybersecurity" data-href="Module 1 - What is Cybersecurity" href="sec-110/module-1-what-is-cybersecurity.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Introduction to Cybersecurity</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 2 - Risk, Adversity, Threats" data-href="Module 2 - Risk, Adversity, Threats" href="sec-110/module-2-risk,-adversity,-threats.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Risk Management</a> - CIA Triad
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 3 &amp; 4 - System Security" data-href="Module 3 &amp; 4 - System Security" href="sec-110/module-3-&amp;-4-system-security.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">System Security &amp; Compliance</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 5 &amp; 6 - Cryptography and Ciphers" data-href="Module 5 &amp; 6 - Cryptography and Ciphers" href="sec-110/module-5-&amp;-6-cryptography-and-ciphers.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cryptography</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 7 - Physical Security" data-href="Module 7 - Physical Security" href="sec-110/module-7-physical-security.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Physical Security</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 8 - Bias" data-href="Module 8 - Bias" href="sec-110/module-8-bias.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bias in Security</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 9 - Intro to Kali" data-href="Module 9 - Intro to Kali" href="sec-110/module-9-intro-to-kali.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Kali Linux</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 10 - Network Security" data-href="Module 10 - Network Security" href="sec-110/module-10-network-security.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Network Security</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 11 - Web Fundamentals" data-href="Module 11 - Web Fundamentals" href="sec-110/module-11-web-fundamentals.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Web Fundamentals</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 12 &amp; 13 - Digital Investigations" data-href="Module 12 &amp; 13 - Digital Investigations" href="sec-110/module-12-&amp;-13-digital-investigations.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Digital Investigations</a> <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary &gt; Threat" data-href="Glossary#Threat" href="glossary.html#Threat" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Threats</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary &gt; Vulnerability" data-href="Glossary#Vulnerability" href="glossary.html#Vulnerability" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Vulnerabilities</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary &gt; Attack" data-href="Glossary#Attack" href="glossary.html#Attack" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Attacks</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Glossary &gt; McCumber Cube" data-href="Glossary#McCumber Cube" href="glossary.html#McCumber Cube" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">McCumber Cube</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Module 3 &amp; 4 - System Security" data-href="Module 3 &amp; 4 - System Security" href="sec-110/module-3-&amp;-4-system-security.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Compliance laws</a>: HIPAA, CFAA, GDPR, CCPA <br>Forensics: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="FOR-120/Evidence Acquisition" data-href="FOR-120/Evidence Acquisition" href="for-120/evidence-acquisition.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Evidence handling</a>
<br>Systems: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="SYS-255/ADDS" data-href="SYS-255/ADDS" href="sys-255/adds.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Active Directory security</a>
<br>Cryptography: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="FOR-120/Evidence Acquisition &gt; Validating Data Acquisition" data-href="FOR-120/Evidence Acquisition#Validating Data Acquisition" href="for-120/evidence-acquisition.html#Validating Data Acquisition" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Hash validation</a>
]]></description><link>sec-110/sec-110-overview.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/SEC-110 Overview.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:24:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Evidence Acquisition]]></title><description><![CDATA[
The ultimate goal of a digital forensics investigation is to preserve, identify, acquire and document digital evidence to be used in the court of law.
Acquisition is the single most important step. You get one chance, because looking through files or booting up the computer will destroy the evidence. Things to consider procedurally: Order of volatility
Imaging methods
Forensic image files formats
Capabilities of imaging tools
Keep continuity in mind.&nbsp;
Write-blockers
Image validation.
Last but most important documentation, aka CoC. Of the types below, the first two can only be captured while the machine being investigated is running.
<img alt="Pasted image 20260124021526.png" src="assets/pasted-image-20260124021526.png" target="_self">
During an investigation, the original evidence cannot be analyzed directly. A copy must be used to avoid contamination. A copy provides the actual data of a file without any extra information, such as the file’s metadata.
Because of the importance of metadata and other information on the drive, digital forensic investigators capture an image of the drive.
Imaging an evidence drive allows capturing the entire drive bit-by-bit, including actual files, data in slack space, swap files, and unallocated space (which may contain deleted files).
If a drive failed, you can replace it with its clone, not its image
Images can be compressed and fragmented Create two images from the evidence drive, hence, in case one got corrupted, the second one can be used for further analysis.
Use two different tools for image acquisition. Photos can be attached to the CoC to show the evidence state at the collection time. This is very important in case of acquiring a powered-on machine, which has running applications on its screen. Acquisition validation is used to ensure that the forensic image is identical to the source.
Validation of digital evidence involves using a hashing algorithm to generate a hash value (aka fingerprint), which is a unique binary or hexadecimal number.
Identical files will always have the same fingerprint even if their names differ.
Integrity check guarantees that the data has not been corrupted or altered during the acquisition process. data integrity should be verified using verification algorithms, such as: Message Digest 5 (MD5) hash
Secure Hash Algorithm 1 (SHA-1)
SHA-2 The physical image is the entire hard drive; it copies all zeroes and ones on the drive. Hence, a physical image of a 1TB drive will generate an image file of size 1 TB. This is the most common in digital forensic and it is important in case you suspect that the evidence has been deleted or modified. The logical image is a part of the hard drive, a certain volume(s) of the drive. For example, if a hard drive contains two partitions, D and E, the logical image would be data from E: drive or D: drive. This is very useful in case you are interested only in the information contained in the drive. In some cases, you know what files you need for the investigation. If the target machine is powered on and running, the acquisition is called live acquisition Live acquisition helps to collect important information, such as memory contents, unencrypted data, passwords, and open network connections. It will be difficult to avoid contamination, since the tools and commands you will use will change the time and date of file access, use DLLs or shared libraries, trigger malware, or even reboot the device. The static acquisition is when the target machine is powered off. In such cases, you could remove the hard drive and connect it to a hardware write-blocker or boot it into a live forensic OS. Write-blockers prevent the modification of the hard drive since the device allows read-only from the evidence drive. Examples of static data are emails, images, word documents, web activity, spreadsheet, slack space, swap files, unallocated drive space, and deleted files. Local acquisition is when you have physical access to the investigated system
While in remote acquisition, you will need network tools to create connections for evidence acquisition.
]]></description><link>for-120/evidence-acquisition.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">FOR-120/Evidence Acquisition.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:38:32 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20260124021526]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="assets/pasted-image-20260124021526.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>assets/pasted-image-20260124021526.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">assets/Pasted image 20260124021526.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:15:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Server Core]]></title><description><![CDATA[To be completed]]></description><link>sys-255/server-core.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/Server Core.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:08:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Powershell]]></title><description><![CDATA[To be completed]]></description><link>sys-255/powershell.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/Powershell.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:08:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Linux]]></title><description><![CDATA[To be completed]]></description><link>sys-255/linux.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/Linux.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:08:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lab Setup]]></title><description><![CDATA[To be completed]]></description><link>sys-255/lab-setup.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/Lab Setup.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:08:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[File Services]]></title><description><![CDATA[To be completed]]></description><link>sys-255/file-services.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/File Services.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:08:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[DHCP]]></title><description><![CDATA[To be completed]]></description><link>sys-255/dhcp.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/DHCP.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:08:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bash]]></title><description><![CDATA[To be completed]]></description><link>sys-255/bash.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/Bash.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:08:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Apache]]></title><description><![CDATA[To be completed]]></description><link>sys-255/apache.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/Apache.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:08:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Connor Schuler - FOR120_Lab2.1_ImageFormat.docx]]></title><link>for-120/lab-deliverables/connor-schuler-for120_lab2.1_imageformat.docx.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">FOR-120/Lab Deliverables/Connor Schuler - FOR120_Lab2.1_ImageFormat.docx.pdf</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:52:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Connor Schuler - FOR120_Lab2.2_PhysicalXLogical.docx]]></title><link>for-120/lab-deliverables/connor-schuler-for120_lab2.2_physicalxlogical.docx.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">FOR-120/Lab Deliverables/Connor Schuler - FOR120_Lab2.2_PhysicalXLogical.docx.pdf</guid><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:17:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title><description><![CDATA[Connor Schuler's Champlain College Tech Journal.]]></description><link>welcome.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Welcome.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 05:22:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[DNS (Domain Name System)]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Extra . at the end of a website domain <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://www.google.com" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://www.google.com" target="_self">www.google.com</a>. <br>User goes to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://www.google.com" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://www.google.com" target="_self">www.google.com</a>
<br>Web browser checks if it knows <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="http://www.google.com" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link is-unresolved" href="http://www.google.com" target="_self">www.google.com</a> 's IP address.
If not, it asks the operating system.
If the operating system doesn't know, it asks a Resolving Name Server Usually automatically defined but might be set manually If the resolving name server doesn't know, it asks the Root domain server. All resolving name servers should know the root name server If the Root domain server doesn't know, it tells the Resolving Name Server to ask the TLD name server (provided by the Root domain server)
If the TLD name server doesn't know, the resolving name server asks the authoritative name server (provided by the TLD server) The TLD Domain Server keeps records of all domain's authoritative domain servers. (ie the .com TLD server knows All .com websites authoritative name servers) The answer from the authoritative name server is then cached by the resolving name server, and passed along to the client operating system. A&nbsp; - Address Record used to resolve a name to an IPv4 address (the most common record)
CNAME - Canonical Name Record used to alias one name to another
AAAA - Address Record used to resolve a name to an IPv6 address&nbsp;
PTR - Pointer Record used to resolve IPv4 address to a name (inverse query)
MX - Mail Exchange used to identify the email servers for a domain&nbsp;
SRV - Service locator used to locate services such as SIP servers, Conference Servers or other services
]]></description><link>sys-255/dns-(domain-name-system).html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/DNS (Domain Name System).md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:11:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[ADDS]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Active Directory Domain Services (AD DS)
DNS (if DNS is not available, Microsoft will install it during the AD setup Wizard)
DHCP
]]></description><link>sys-255/adds.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/ADDS.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:09:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[index]]></title><description><![CDATA[Connor Schuler's Champlain College Tech Journal.]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:55:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Forensic Image Formats]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Raw bit by bit copy
Will create the same size, even if disk is mostly empty
No additional metadata about the image itself (name, size, timestamps, and other info in the images inode) Cryptographic hashing
improved error handling
logging
performance enhancements (compression)
verification checking
progress monitoring Proprietary format
supports features like metadata, compression, encryption, hashing, and split files
Forensic file formats are sometimes called evidence containers Proprietary format from AccessData
Supports many features, such as metadata, compression, encryption, hashing, and split files Included all expect features of a forensic format, and additional encryption
Open source implementation and extensible file format for storing disk images and associated metadata
]]></description><link>for-120/forensic-image-formats.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">FOR-120/Forensic Image Formats.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:48:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Connor Schuler - FOR120_Lab1.1_CreatingVHD.docx]]></title><link>for-120/lab-deliverables/connor-schuler-for120_lab1.1_creatingvhd.docx.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">FOR-120/Lab Deliverables/Connor Schuler - FOR120_Lab1.1_CreatingVHD.docx.pdf</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:29:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Connor Schuler - SEC-260 - Basic HTML Page Lab Deliverables]]></title><link>sec-260/lab-deliverables/connor-schuler-sec-260-basic-html-page-lab-deliverables.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-260/Lab Deliverables/Connor Schuler - SEC-260 - Basic HTML Page Lab Deliverables.pdf</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:46:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Connor Schuler - SEC-260 - Basic Web Server Lab Deliverables]]></title><link>sec-260/lab-deliverables/connor-schuler-sec-260-basic-web-server-lab-deliverables.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-260/Lab Deliverables/Connor Schuler - SEC-260 - Basic Web Server Lab Deliverables.pdf</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 19:46:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Storage Devices]]></title><description><![CDATA[Four Categories of storage media:
Magnetic media Hard Disks and Tapes Non-volatile memory (flash)
Optical media. <img alt="Pasted image 20260117002459.png" src="assets/pasted-image-20260117002459.png" target="_self"> Versions/Speeds 1.5 Gb/s for SATA 1
3.0 Gb/s for SATA 2
6 Gb/s (~700MB/s) for SATA 3
16 Gb/s for SATA 3.2 has card-edge connector Versions/Speeds 3 Gb/s for SAS 1
6 Gb/s for SAS 2
12 Gb/s for SAS 3
22.5 Gb/s for SAS 4 Same connector/interface as SATA, but has separator aka Scuzzy
up to 320 Mb/s
SCSI-2: 50-pin interface, Molex power
SCSI-3: 68-pin interface, Molex power
SCSI-3 variant: 80-pin interface 133 Mb/s
has pin connector
40-position connector; 39-pin interface
IDE drive jumper options Master
Slave
Cable select
Note original jumper setting prior to imaging Standard power connector
HDDs has 3 storage sizes:
3.5 in
2.5 in
1.8 in
Parts of a drive:
**
round flat, magnetic or ceramic discs in a hard drive that holds the actual data Made of two materials Substrate Material Magnetic Media Coating Each platter has two sides sides are numbered starting at 0 Most drives have multiple platters Each platter has tracks, which is where data is stores Most platters have 10k+ tracks
Track numbering start at 0 from the outside
Stacks of tracks are called cylinders Number of cylinders (tracks), heads (sides), and sectors (aka CHS) uniquely identify the physical geometry of the storage units on a disk CHS also yields disk capacity:
Capacity = Cylinders x Heads x Sectors x sector size
<br><img alt="Pasted image 20260116134011.png" src="assets/pasted-image-20260116134011.png" target="_self"> Trend toward less platters with more density Each track has sectors 1 sector = 512 bytes (sometimes 4096) and a few extra "info bits" Info bits include ID info, synchronization fields, and ECC data. Sectors can turn bad beacuse of: excessive read/writes
some viruses
voltage surges Drives have reserved sectors, which are used as others fail
bad sectors are difficult to see by normal operating systems, requires special hardware Data on HDDs can be spread out, called fragmentation.
Fragmentation increases seek time/delay SSDs use flash based storage and a controller Constant seek time
No file fragmentation issues
No moving parts no mechanical failures
fast startup time
no motor noise Lighter weight
low power Overwriting process is complicated &amp; expensive read-erase-modify-write cycle Cells have limited life/cycles Wear leveling must be used SSDs are significantly harder to save data from 1 page = 8 sections/sectors (512 bytes)
Pages make up blocks
<br><img alt="Pasted image 20260116235700.png" src="assets/pasted-image-20260116235700.png" target="_self"> Write is fast
But rewrite/overwrite involves additional erasing step
Entire Blocks (not pages or sections) must be erased
<br><img alt="Pasted image 20260117000152.png" src="assets/pasted-image-20260117000152.png" target="_self">
Grey = unused page
blue = in-use page
Optimization strategies <br><img alt="Pasted image 20260117000904.png" src="assets/pasted-image-20260117000904.png" target="_self"> Garbage collection <br><img alt="Pasted image 20260117001023.png" src="assets/pasted-image-20260117001023.png" target="_self"> Individual memory cells have limited read/write cycles (5000 – 50000)
Like hard disks SSDs have extra capacity not accessible by normal users
Unlike hard disks Approx. 10-25% more storage than stated capacity, Overprovisioned areas are continuously used File Deletion on a normal HDD File is marked as deleted in the File system’s database
HDD has no clue which sectors are freed up
TRIM marks data blocks as stale SSDs need to know this info. Modern OS have support for this command ]]></description><link>for-120/storage-devices.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">FOR-120/Storage Devices.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:52:41 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20260117002459]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="assets/pasted-image-20260117002459.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>assets/pasted-image-20260117002459.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">assets/Pasted image 20260117002459.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:24:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20260117001023]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="assets/pasted-image-20260117001023.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>assets/pasted-image-20260117001023.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">assets/Pasted image 20260117001023.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:10:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20260117000904]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="assets/pasted-image-20260117000904.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>assets/pasted-image-20260117000904.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">assets/Pasted image 20260117000904.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:09:04 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20260117000152]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="assets/pasted-image-20260117000152.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>assets/pasted-image-20260117000152.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">assets/Pasted image 20260117000152.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 05:01:52 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20260116235700]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="assets/pasted-image-20260116235700.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>assets/pasted-image-20260116235700.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">assets/Pasted image 20260116235700.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 04:57:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20260116235652]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="assets/pasted-image-20260116235652.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>assets/pasted-image-20260116235652.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">assets/Pasted image 20260116235652.png</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 04:56:52 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pasted image 20260116134011]]></title><description><![CDATA[<img src="assets/pasted-image-20260116134011.png" target="_self">]]></description><link>assets/pasted-image-20260116134011.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">assets/Pasted image 20260116134011.png</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:40:11 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="."&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Connor Schuler - SYS-255 Lab01 Deliverables]]></title><link>sys-255/lab-deliverables/connor-schuler-sys-255-lab01-deliverables.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/Lab Deliverables/Connor Schuler - SYS-255 Lab01 Deliverables.pdf</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Connor Schuler - SYS-255 Remote Access Spot Check Deliverables]]></title><link>sys-255/lab-deliverables/connor-schuler-sys-255-remote-access-spot-check-deliverables.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/Lab Deliverables/Connor Schuler - SYS-255 Remote Access Spot Check Deliverables.pdf</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 03:13:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 3 & 4 - System Security]]></title><description><![CDATA[Bit-level data: storage, transfer, and bit-level operations of data (input/output, processing)
System-level data: roles and authorized resources to be used for reading, writing, and data processing
Personal-level data: SSN, username/passwords, address, biometrics, medical history, credit history, background checks, recordings, grades…
Policy-level data: Rules how to protect data on all the levels above.&nbsp;
McCumber Cube
Security Goals&nbsp;
Information States&nbsp;
Countermeasures (security controls)
Data protection laws
HIPAA
CFAA
GDPR
CCPA
**]]></description><link>sec-110/module-3-&amp;-4-system-security.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 3 &amp; 4 - System Security.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:52:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 5 & 6 - Cryptography and Ciphers]]></title><description><![CDATA[Confidentiality: Using cryptography to keep data private
Integrity: Using cryptography to ensure that data has not been altered
Authentication: Verifying that user is who they claim
Non-repudiation: Ensure that user performed activity by proof that they cannot denyNon-Repudiation: Digital signatures, digital certificates.
Cryptographic Salt: add a string of random characters to a password before it is hashed and stored to create an extra layer of randomness.
Steganography is the practice of concealing information within another message or physical object to avoid detection.]]></description><link>sec-110/module-5-&amp;-6-cryptography-and-ciphers.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 5 &amp; 6 - Cryptography and Ciphers.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:51:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 12 & 13 - Digital Investigations]]></title><link>sec-110/module-12-&amp;-13-digital-investigations.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 12 &amp; 13 - Digital Investigations.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:50:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 11 - Web Fundamentals]]></title><link>sec-110/module-11-web-fundamentals.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 11 - Web Fundamentals.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:49:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 10 - Network Security]]></title><link>sec-110/module-10-network-security.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 10 - Network Security.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:49:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 9 - Intro to Kali]]></title><link>sec-110/module-9-intro-to-kali.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 9 - Intro to Kali.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:48:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 8 - Bias]]></title><link>sec-110/module-8-bias.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 8 - Bias.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:48:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 7 - Physical Security]]></title><link>sec-110/module-7-physical-security.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 7 - Physical Security.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 02:47:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 2 - Risk, Adversity, Threats]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Confidentiality
Integrity
Availability
]]></description><link>sec-110/module-2-risk,-adversity,-threats.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 2 - Risk, Adversity, Threats.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:06:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Module 1 - What is Cybersecurity]]></title><description><![CDATA[First iteration Arpanet in 1969
Eventually led to worldwide web administered by ICANN
First virus documented creeper, self replicating, non-malious
1968: Internet Engineering Task Force created
1990: Arpanet decommissioned, administration given to NSFNET
1991: World Wide Web introduced
1995: private sector takes over internet, NSFNET dissolved
3 policy areas
Online rights
Cybersec
Data privacy
Cyber-attack motives
Cyber crime Crypto
Money
Identify theft IP theft Software
Designs
Movies
music Espionage spying Terrorism Propaganda, diversions, etc Hacktivism Defacement, DoS, etc Messing around
Each incident in 2020 cost on average ½ million in damages
Majority of internet is underseas cabling
Data stored in large power hungry datacenters
Different countries have different views of network administration
US and Allies: open internet
China: closed internet with heavy controls in/out
]]></description><link>sec-110/module-1-what-is-cybersecurity.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SEC-110/Module 1 - What is Cybersecurity.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:05:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[DNS]]></title><link>sys-255/dns.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">SYS-255/DNS.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 07:09:25 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>